# AZEEZ BABARINDE

# Data Analyst

Data Analyst with a background in science and research. Experienced in presenting complex information in an understandable and engaging way. Completed analysis projects across multiple fields, including health care, engineering, agriculture, ecommerce, logistics and tobacco.

■ babarindeazeez.s@gmail.com

Perlin, Germany (unlimited work permit)

zeezki.github.io

+4915218174952

in linkedin.com/in/azeezbabarinde

github.com/zeezki

# **EDUCATION**

# **Data Analytics Certification,**

CareerFoundry

06/2021 – 10/2021 Berlin, Germany

# Masters of Science in Environmental and Resource Management,

Brandenburg University of Technology 08/2019 – 07/2023 Cottbus Germany

# Diploma in Web Design,

HIIT Plc

04/2016 - 07/2016 Ikeja, Nigeria

# Bachelor of Agriculture (Soil Science and Land Management),

Federal University of Agriculture 09/2009 - 11/2014 Abeokuta, Nigeria

#### Computer Systems Technician (Diploma),

Michelon Computer Institute 10/2007 - 06/2008 Lagos, Nigeria

# **SKILLS / TOOLS**

- Advanced Analytics
- Data Visualization (Tableau, Data studio, Power BI)
- MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Words, VBA)
- Google Workspace(Docs, Sheets, Slides)
- Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Scipy, Seaborn)
- SQL (GBQ, PostgreSQL)
- Story telling with data
- Machine Learning (Supervised and Unsupervised)
- Hypothesis testing
- Ticket Support (JIRA)
- HTML / CSS

# LANGUAGES

English – *Native User* Deutsch – *A2* 

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Data Manager**

JTI (Japan Tobacco International) Trier, Germany 03/2023 - Current

- Developed data extraction tool to SDS manager to reduce manual data entry time by 95%
- Built a visualization tool to monitor the safety data sheets requests on various KPIs
- Created an automation tool to optimize manual chemical inventory calculation, reducing task time by over 90%

## **Business Analyst - Internship**

Wayfair *Berlin, Germany* 07/2022 - 01/2023

- Provided excellent customer services and training on tooluse to Suppliers and warehouse managers for conversion.
- Built a visualizations tool to give visibility over late orders for the company's warehouse.

# **Data Analyst**

ELALAN Construction Company

08/2021 - 02/2022

 Developed KPI to monitor company sales and decreased cost by 20%.

#### **Data Analyst**

Self-employed - Freelance 08/2020 - 08/2021

 Performed cleansing, processing, and validation on data to analyze, to ensure its quality.

#### **Data Analyst**

Stanfrey Engineering Limited 12/2016 - 07/2020

 Conveyed analysis findings through reports, dashboards, and visualizations, saving 10 hours of weekly manual reporting.

#### Web Analyst - Internship

HIIT Plc 08/2016 - 11/2016

# **Computer Science Teacher (National Youth Service)**

N.K.S.T Girls secondary school 05/2015 - 05/2016

03/2013 - 03/2010

# **PROJECTS**

EA Sports FIFA player ratings

